Demonstration of sd-boot in Qemu Virtual Machine
The default view — countdown to boot the default entry
↓ (down key pressed)
↓
This entry is autogenerated
Macintosh and Microsoft systems are also autodetected
↑
There's just one "Fedora 34" entry, so it is shown without the kernel version.
There's just one "Fedora 34" entry, so it is shown without the kernel version. There are two "Fedora Linux 36" entries, kernel version is shown to disambiguate.
h — open a short help menu
d — mark/unmark entry as default
The default is displayed with a small triangle (▶)
+/- – increase/decrease boot menu timeout
+ +/- – increase/decrease boot menu timeout
+
-
When menu is disabled, any key held when sd-boot activates will open the menu
e — open an bare-bones editor for the kernel commandline of the selected entry
general shell / emacs keybindings work:
← (left), → (right), Home, End
alt-b (jump word forward) alt-f (jump word back)
backspace (delete character) ctrl-w (delete word back) alt-d (delete word forward) ctrl-k (delete everything)
Enter to boot
Enter to boot (or Esc to cancel)
r — change resolution (font size)
r — change resolution (font size) (For some reason, this barely has any effect in Qemu…
r — change resolution (font size) (For some reason, this barely has any effect in Qemu, but it usually works fine on real hardware.)
r — change resolution (font size) (For some reason, this barely has any effect in Qemu, but it usually works fine on real hardware.) Changing resolution is useful for HiDPI displays.
For quick multiboot: l — boot the first Linux entry w — boot Windows a — boot Micintosh f — boot into firmware configuration
p — print debug information
(resolution was changed in the video here to fit the whole text)
Information about the firmware, sd-boot, the display, and individual entries is displayed.
That's all folks! Enter — boot selected entry